Matsuda! This isn't child's play! Don't be flippant!
松田、子供の遊びじゃないんだ
浮ついた事を言うな
Understood...
はい…
This is about the Kira investigation! Will you take it seriously?!
これはキラ事件なんだ、もっと真面目にやってくれよ！
S-Sorry...
す…すみません……
Matsuda!!
松田！
I mean, Matsuda-san, please stop.
いや、松田さん止めてください
"Matsuda"?
松田…
I don't want to be a dead weight around here.
ここのお荷物になりたくないからな
R-Ryuuzaki, is there anything else I can do? Other than being a manager?
竜…竜崎
僕にも、何かやれる事ありませんか？
R-Ryuuzaki, is there anything else I can do? Other than being a manager?
マネージャー以外に…
Then, can you bring me another cup of coffee?
じゃあコーヒーのおかわり持ってきてください
え……
I too... want to play a bigger role in this!
Matsuda
I love you...
君を愛してる…
だからお願いだ、帰るなんて言わないでくれ
So, please, don't tell me that you're leaving.
I want to be by your side forever.
ずっと、そばにいて…
あっ、監督
Director!
Please, Misa has a boyfriend, so love scenes are no good!
海砂、彼氏いるんで、ラブシーンは NG でお願いします
Huh?! W-Wait...
ちょ、ちょっと…何言ってんの、今更……
What are you saying all of a sudden?!
We can just pretend to kiss.
キスはしてる振りだけに
え～そんなこと言ってたら映画撮れないよ…
If you say things like that, we'll never get this movie finished!
I said no, and I mean no!
ダメたらダメ～！
The Yotsuba Group's Tokyo Headquarters.
ヨツバグループ東京本社…
Today is Friday!
今日は金曜…
All the deaths which benefit Yotsuba happen towards the end of the week.
ヨツバにとって都合のよい死は、週末に集中している
I don't want to be a dead weight around here.
ここのお荷物になりたくないからな
There was always something amazing about Mogi-san.
模木さんは何気に凄いですよ
Matsuda! This isn't child's play!
松田！子供の遊びじゃないんだ
Will you take it seriously?!
もっと真面目にやってくれよ！
Well, Matsuda-san is a bit of an airhead by nature.
松田さんは天然だから…
コーヒーのおかわり持ってきてください
Bring me another cup of coffee.
Matsuda!!
松田！
Matsu! Hey, Matsu!!
マッツー
ね、マッツーってば
He seems to have gone off somewhere.
どっか行きましたよ
Huh?!
はぁ？
In that case, let's try starting with the names on this list.
だからとりあえず、このリストから建ってみてくれ
Understood.
わかりました
If it was possible to kill someone by merely knowing their name and face, would I try to kill criminals?
ちから
もし仮に、顔と名前で人を殺せる能力があったとしたら
If it was possible to kill someone by merely knowing their name and face, would I try to kill criminals?
僕は悪人を裁こうとするだろうか…
I do believe there are people in this world that are better off dead...
…確かに世の中、いない方がいいと思う人間はいる
but I wouldn't take it upon myself and become a murderer to make the world a better place.
しかし自らが殺人犯になって、
世の中を変えようとまで、僕は思わない
No, I'm thinking about this too much.
…いや、考えすぎた
There's no way I'd forget about killing so many people--
大量の殺人をして、その記憶が残ら…
What's the matter?
どうしました？
Why are you staring at me?
そんなにこっちらを見つめて
Are you annoyed that I'm the only one with cake to eat?
やはり私だけがケーキを食べていることにムカつかれたんですね
No, it's nothing like that.
あっいや、そうじゃないよ
Here.
はい
I'm not envious.
羨ましがってない
竜崎
Ryuuzaki.
What's up, Watari?
どうした、ワタリ
The detective Erald Coil has been commissioned to "reveal L's identity".
探偵のエラルド．コイルのところに、
L の正体を明かして欲しいという依頼が…
Erald Coil, the famous detective said to be second only to L.
エラルド．コイルと言えば、
L に次ぐ名探偵と言われている男じゃないか
一体誰がそんな依頼を…
Who would commission this?
We've determined that the commission came from Kida Masahiko, the Planning Director of the Yotsuba Group's Tokyo Headquarters.
依頼主は、ヨツバグループ東京本社、
ライツ企画部長、樹多正彦と突き止めました
So, it is Yotsuba's work!
やはりヨツバか
Yotsuba has got to be working with Kira.
ヨツバは、キラと繋がってる
L の正体を欲しがってるとすれば、L を殺すつもりってことだろうね
They want L's identity, so that they can kill L.
This is bad. We're already understaffed, and now we have this Coil to worry about.
まずいな…
人手がないのに、コイルの方にも気を配る必要があるわけか…
It's fine.
大丈夫ですよ
The detective known as Erald Coil is me.
エラルド．コイルという探偵も私ですから
The three most famous detectives in this world at the moment... L, Coil and Deneuve... are all me.
今、世界の三大探偵と言われている、
L 、コイル、ドヌーヴ、皆私です
The three most famous detectives in this world at the moment... L, Coil and Deneuve... are all me.
A lot of people who try to find me fall for this.
私を探そうとする者は、結構これに引っ掛かります
If you keep this secret, this strawberry is yours.
イチゴあげますから、秘密にしといてください
Impressive as always, Ryuuzaki.
さすがだな、竜崎
It might be better to try and blend in and get out of here.
このまま紛れて帰ったほうがいいか…
No! Then me coming here would mean nothing.
いや、それじゃ入った意味が無い
Should I wait for everyone to go before searching the building?
誰もいなくなるまで待って、社内中物色するか
But what if I get caught?
…いや、そんなことして捕まったら…
Maybe it's better if I leave...
やっぱり、帰ったほうが…
Jeez, tonight again? I'm really not in the mood for this...
はぁ…今日もあれか…
だるいな…
At least it's the weekend; if we had these drawn out secret meetings on a Monday, it'd be hard for me to bring myself to work.
でも週末だからまだいいんだ
あんな何時終わるかわからない極秘会議、
月曜だったら会社来るの憂鬱になる
Secret meetings?!
極秘の会議…
Bingo!
ビンゴか!?
The nineteenth floor.
十九階…
I've come this far...
ここまで来たんだ…
I'm going to do this!
やってやる！
Okay, I've got to get close to this guy? Leave it to me.
オッケー、彼に近付けばいいんだな
任せてくれ
So, you want me to hack the surveillance cameras and security system at Yotsuba Group's Tokyo Headquarters?
で、私はこいつのいるヨツバ東京本社の、
監視カメラや防犯システムを破れるようにしとけばいいのね
So, you want me to hack the surveillance cameras and security system at Yotsuba Group's Tokyo Headquarters?
Yes.
はい
It's safe to assume that there's definitely a connection between Kira and the Yotsuba Group.
キラとヨツバは間違いなく関係していると考えでいいでしょう
First, we need to investigate Yotsuba, and determine exactly who, and how many, have this power.
まずヨツバを洗って
ちから
誰か能力を持っているのか、
何人持っているのか、完璧に把握する必要があります
First, we need to investigate Yotsuba, and determine exactly who, and how many, have this power.
Most importantly, we must ensure that the Yotsuba Group doesn't discover that we're investigating them.
絶対にヨツバに我々が調べていることを気づかれてはなりません
Just consider that if you're caught, our chance of catching Kira will disappear then and there.
気づかれたら、その時点で
キラは捕まえられなくなるぐらいに考えてください
くそ…はっきり聞こえないな…
Damn it, I can't hear this clearly...
If I could just overhear one important thing...
何か一言でも、確信的なことが聞ければ…
He's just in our way... we should kill him and let our share prices rise...
…あいつはもう「ヤメ」と言うか、邪魔だろ
殺して株分けちまおう
They just said "kill"!
今「殺す」って聞こえた…
Kira-sama is really...
まったくキラ様…
キラ!?
"Kira"?! They said "Kira"! They said it!
出たキラ、出た…
They're getting Kira to kill someone?
えっ、キラに殺してもらう…聞こえたぞ！
Yes! I heard it!!
こいつらやっぱりキラと…
They're definitely connected to Kira. I did it! What an achievement!!
やったぞ…大手柄だ！
Who the hell are you?!
何だお前！
くれぐれも焦った行動や先走った行動など、
一人の判断で動かないように
Please, think ahead carefully before you act, and don't do anything rash.
Ryuuzaki.
竜崎
What is it, Watari?
どうした、ワタリ
松田さんが、ベルトで緊急サインを送ってきました
We've received a distress signal from Matsuda-san's belt.
Where from?
…どこから？
Well, it seems to be originating from Yotsuba Group's Tokyo Headquarters.
それが…
どうやら、ヨツバの東京本社内からのようで…
Well, it seems to be originating from Yotsuba Group's Tokyo Headquarters.
I-I'm Matsui Tarou, a manager at Yoshida Productions.
私、ヨシダプロダクションでマネージメントをしております
松井太郎と申します
How would you like to hire our number one recommended, multi-talented star, Amane Misa, for your commercials?
今うちで一押しのマルチタレント、
弥海砂を、御社のイメージキャラとして…
CM に、いかがでしょうか…
Please, just forget everything I've just said.
今までの話は忘れてください
We need to rethink our plan.
作戦考え直しです
Matsuda, you idiot...
松田の馬鹿…
Yoshida Productions... Matsui Tarou...
ヨシダプロダクション、松井太郎
He doesn't seem to have anything suspicious on him.
怪しい物はもっていないな
I doubt he's an industrial spy.
産業スパイではなさそうだ
Yes... erm, I hope you will consider Misa-Misa...
はい…
あの…是非、ミサミサをお願いしま…す
These two are most likely keeping an eye on me, while the rest of them are in the meeting room, deciding how to dispose of me.
この二人は見張り、
会議室で残る者は僕の処分を話し合ってるはずだ…
I'm as good as dead...
やっぱり殺される…
I wonder if they've received my distress signal?
緊急サイン、届いてるのかな…
I wonder if Ryuuzaki will bother to try and save me?
っていうか、竜崎は僕のこと助けてくれるのかな…
I wonder what's going to happen to me...
どうなるんだろう、僕…
It's alright, you can answer that.
出ていいですよ
ただしここにいる事は言わず、
少し耳から離して、我々にも話が聞こえるように
Just don't mention that you're here.
Also, hold the phone away from your ear so that we can listen in.
O-Okay.
あ…はい
Hello?
もしもし…
Yo, Matsui!
よう～松井
Ryuuzaki!!
竜崎…
It's Asahi, long time no talk.
俺だ、朝日だ
おひさ～っ
Hey, Asahi, how's it going?
おお…朝日、ひさしぶり
Doesn't sound like you're outside... you at home?
お外じゃないみたいだな…もう家か？
あ…ああ……
Err, yeah...
You alone?
今…一人？
Yeah, I'm alone. What's up?
うん、一人だよ、なに？
He's not with Amane Misa, Matsuda is alone.
弥海砂は別行動、松田は一人です
Fancy going out for a drink?
今から飲みに行かないか？
What? Now? Sorry, not tonight...
えっ、今から？
…悪い、今日はやめとくよ
What, don't tell me your finances are in a pinch again?
何だよ…また財布がピンチなのかぁ？
"Pinch"?
ピンチ…
Yeah, they're in quite a "pinch" at the moment. You got me!
ああっ…かなりピンチなんだ
そういうことバレバレだな、ははは…
Matsuda is in quite a pinch.
松田かなりピンチです
しょうがない、また改めて誘おうよ、じゃなぁ
Never mind, another time then. See ya.
S-So, what do you think of Misa-Misa? I'm sure she'll be an asset to your company.
あっ、それでいいですね
ミサミサ、どうでしょう？
必ず、お力になれると思います…
S-So, what do you think of Misa-Misa? I'm sure she'll be an asset to your company.
If you're serious about promoting her, shouldn't you have brought her here?
売り込みに来るなら、本人も連れてくるべきでは？
ほんっとうにマネージャーなんでしょうね
Are you really her manager?
Well, she's currently shooting a movie nearby, I'll call her over as soon as she's done.
いや…今、近くで映画の撮影中でして…
ロケが終わったら、すぐこちらへ呼びます
Please consider using Misa-Misa as your image in your commercials.
是非、御社のイメージキャラに…
For now, I've got to keep stalling!
とりあえず、時間を稼ぐしかない…
Misa's phone is going straight to the answering machine.
海砂の電話は留守電になってる
I'll send a message telling her to call us.
一応こっちに電話するように、伝言しておいた
What should we do, Ryuuzaki?
どうする、竜崎…
Let's see, if Matsuda-san dies now, it'll confirm the Yotsuba Group's guilt.
そうですね…
これで松田さんが死んだら、
ヨツバの疑惑は確定的になりますが…
For the moment, let's just see what unfolds.
とりあえず、少し様子を見ましょう
What shall we do?
どうする？
It all depends on whether or not he overheard our discussion.
問題は話を聞かれたかどうかだ…
The possibility's there. There's no other choice than to kill him.
可能性はあるんだ、殺しておくしかない
But is he really here merely to promote a "talent"? Surely he's not from the police?
しかし本当に、タレントの売り込みに来たのか？
まさか警察ってことは…
That's impossible. The Japanese police should have abandoned the Kira investigation by now.
それはないだろう
日本警察は完全にキラ事件から手を引いている
It doesn't matter who he is, we've got to kill him.
「何者か」なんて関係ない
殺すしかないんだ…
It's true that she might actually be a good image for us.
確かに…イメージキャラっていうのはいいかもしれないな
でしょ？もうすぐロケ終わりますから…
Don't you agree?!
Her shoot should finish soon, so please wait.
お待ちください
Jeez, I'm so tired...
う…ん～～疲れた…
Yay, a message from Light.
えっ、ライトからの伝言
やっぱり遅くなると心配してくれるのね
He must be worried about me, since it's so late.
Misa.
海砂
Light! I'm sorry, but I've been working all this time. I'm done now!
ライト～お仕事ばっかってゴメンね、もう終わるから
Misa, you're not with Matsuda-san then?
海砂、松田さんと一緒じゃないんだな
He's such a disgrace. He just abandoned Misa!
あいつサイテー、海砂のことほったらかして…
My work cell phone is ringing...
お仕事用の携帯に電話入った
Huh? It's Matsu.
これマッツーからだよ
Matsuda-san is calling Misa.
松田さんから海砂に電話が入った
Ask Misa-san to enable us to hear.
海砂さんにこっちにも話が聞こえるようにと…
Misa-Misa, as soon as filming finishes, I need you to head over to the Yotsuba Group's Tokyo Headquarters.
ミサミサ、撮影終わったら、すぐヨツバの東京本社に来てくれ
You could get the chance to appear in their commercials.
もしかしたら、ヨツバさんの CM に出られるかもしれない
今、交渉中だ
Currently, I'm in the middle of negotiating a deal for you.
Oh, really?! That's amazing, Matsu! So that's what you were doing!
えっ、マジで？
すっごいマッツー
そんな営業してたんだ
Misa will give it everything she got!
海砂気合入れていくよ～ ≧▽≦/
Okay, take a taxi, and you'll be here in no time.
うん、タクシー飛ばしてくれば、すぐだよ
Yagami-kun, we may be able to save Matsuda-san, but we will need Misa-san's help.
夜神君
松田さんを助けられるかもしれません
Yagami-kun, we may be able to save Matsuda-san, but we will need Misa-san's help.
海砂さんの協力が必要ですが、
夜神君の言うことなら聞いてくれるでしょう
She'll listen to you.
Hi, I'm Misa-Misa!
ミサミサで～す
ヌードにはなりませんが、水着や下着までならオッケーです
Misa doesn't do nudes, but underwear or swimsuits are fine!
Pleased to meet you!
よろしくお願いしま～す
Hmm, she's ridiculously cute in the flesh...
うん…本物はものすごく可愛いな…
今は、そういう問題じゃないんじゃないか
Surely that's not the issue right now...
Matsu, the production company gave the go-ahead for a special reception especially for Yotsuba-san.
マッツー、ヨツバさんだし、
事務所からスペシャル接待のオッケー出たよ
Matsu, the production company gave the go-ahead for a special reception especially for Yotsuba-san.
Huh? Special?
えっ、スペシャル…？
Good evening! Pleased to meet you!
こんばんは
よろしくお願いしま～す
Tonight, the girls from our production team would like to provide you all with a special reception!
今夜は事務所の女の子たちみ～んなで、おもてなしま～す
…おい、何か方向おかしくなってないか？
Oi, I think we're starting to go off on a tangent here...
It can't be helped; for now, we've got to stay close to that manager.
仕方がないだろ
今はあのマネージャーから離れるわけにはいかない
So, we may as well enjoy ourselves.
どうせなら俺は楽しむ
Ryuuzaki and the others should be able to see us in here.
ここなら、竜崎達が見ることができる
We might be saved.
…助かるかも
Okay, drink up! Drink up!
はい、飲んで、飲んで
This has got to be heaven!
これは天国だな、ははは…
Misa-san... she's not bad at this, is she?
海砂さん、結構やりますね
さてと…
Okay then...
I'm just going to the toilet.
ちょっとトイレ…
竜崎、見てますか？
Ryuuzaki, can you see me?
Yes.
はい
I'm sorry, I--
あの…すみません、僕…
Never mind about that now.
そんな事はもういいです
Right. The eight that are here were in a meeting together, planning who to have Kira murder.
はい
今来た八人、
キラを使って、殺しようする会議をしてました
Right. The eight that are here were in a meeting together, planning who to have Kira murder.
はっきり聞きました、もう完璧奴等ですよ
I heard them clearly.
Without a doubt, it's them.
Are you absolutely sure?
本当でしょうね
If it's true, they'll be aiming to kill you.
しかしそれを聞いたのなら、
松田さんを殺そうと思ってるはずです
I thought as much. Is there really no way to save me?
あ…やっぱり……
助かる方法はないでしょうか？
Luckily, you're still alive, so there's a chance that we can save you.
幸いまだ生きているので、助かるかもしれません
それには…
But to do that... you've got to die before you're killed.
殺される前に死ぬことです
Huh?!
Understand? Listen carefully...
いいですか
よく聞いてください
What?!
えっ？まさか…
No way...
That's stupid...
そんな…馬鹿な……
そうなんですか？
我が社はまだまだ発展している…
What's going on?!
なんだ？
Man, I'm so drunk...
いや～ぁ、はは、酔った酔った
I feel so good!
気持ちいい
よう、皆さん、楽しいんでますか～？
Hey, everyone! Are you all having fun? You should be!
ダメですよ、楽しまなきゃ
Now everyone, this is what you've all been waiting for! It's Matsui Tarou Showtime!
さぁ皆さん…お待ちかね
松井太郎、ショーターイム！
Hey, what the hell do you think you're doing?
おい、何するつもりだ？
Yay! Go for it, Matsui-san!
きゃ～～っ、松井さん、がんばーー
Woo-aah!
あらよっと…
Hey! That's dangerous! You're drunk!
おい、酔ってるのに危ないぞ
It's fine, I do this all the time...
大～丈夫ですよ…
いつもやってるから…
よっと
Cut it out!
やめるって…
あぶねぇ！馬鹿！
That's dangerous, you idiot!!
止めろ
I'm... fine...
大丈夫ですよ……
H-He fell!!
落ちた！
This is bad...
やばいぞ…
Oh, no! I heard a huge bang and came out to see what happened...
OH～ NO
ドンって音がしたから来てみたらタイ～ヘン
１１９、１１９
119! 119!
119 is the emergency telephone number in Japan
God... what an awful role to play...
まったく…嫌な役だなぁ……
Leave this to us, gentlemen. Hurry up and get out of here!
皆さん、ここは私たちに任せて、早くお帰りを…
Y-You sure?
えっ、そんな…
We'll be fine. Please, keep me in mind for the commercial.
大丈夫です、… CM の件、お願いしますね
Hurry! If the paparazzi catch us, it'll be troublesome.
急げ、こんなところマスコミに見られたら、面倒だ
What, what's going on?! A jumper?!
なになに、飛び降り？
どうあれ、目の前で死んでくれてよかった…
Well, at least he died in front of us.
おい
あ～あ…人手がないとはいえ私まで…こんなの嫌ですよ
I know we're understaffed, but I can't believe I got dragged into this.
Matsuda, you idiot...
松田の馬鹿
弥海砂のマネージャー、死亡…
Amane Misa's manager, dead...
Yes?
はい
ヨツバグループ東京本社、
ライツ企画部部長…樹多正彦さんですね
Is this the Planning Director at Yotsuba Group's Tokyo Headquarters, Kida Masahiko?
Ah, that is correct. Who is this?
ああ、そうだが…お宅は？
エラルド．コイルと申します
The name's Erald Coil.
I'd like your advice on a certain issue.
条件について、ご相談を…
An advance of $2 million, and $8 million for a successful completion? Is he serious?!
前金200万ドル、成功報酬800万ドル…
正気か…
On top of that, he's demanded $2 million for his silence if we don't go ahead with it.
さらに、依頼しない場合でも、口止め料を200万ドルだそうだ
Buying his silence, huh? It's best to assume that he already knows something.
口止め料か…
コイルはもうかなりのところまで
わかっていると考えた方がいいな
This is getting too dangerous! I want out.
…やばいじゃないか
僕はもうこの会議からぬける…
I've got no clue to which one of you is Kira, but I don't want to get too deep in this and end up being arrested!
誰かキラか知らないが、
巻き添えになって逮捕されるなんてごめんだ！
I've got no clue to which one of you is Kira, but I don't want to get too deep in this and end up being arrested!
うわはは…
Hatori... you're going to be dead tomorrow.
葉鳥…
お前、明日には死んでるな
Hatori... you're going to be dead tomorrow.
Wait, that was just a joke!
待て…今のは冗談だ……
I'm in! I'll do this properly!
やる！ちゃんとやるから…
So, what're we gonna do? Even if Coil knows something, he's still willing to take it on.
で、どうする？
コイルは知っても、なお依頼を受けようとしている
So, what're we gonna do? Even if Coil knows something, he's still willing to take it on.
As long as we give him the money, he's on our side. That's all there is to it.
金さえ出せば仲間になる…そういうことか
We've got to keep a shrewd guy like him on our side.
コイルのような切れ者は、味方につけておかなければ駄目だ
You're right; it doesn't matter how much we've got to pay.
そうだ…買え、いくら出しでもだ…
Yeah, that's right! Buy him off!
…そうだそうだ、買え！
Okay, this contract with Coil, any objections?
よし、コイルと契約だ
異議はないな
No objections.
異議なし
L, you listening?
L 、聞いてる？
What a disappointment. The security levels here are terrible.
もう拍子抜けよ
ここのセキュリティレベルはサイテーね
警備会社と契約してるだけ、盗聴探知器さえなかったわよ
All they've got is a contract with some security firm... not even any measures to detect bugging devices.
I-It's been a week since I infiltrated that place.
ぼ…僕が潜入してから一週間…
なんか、ものすごく出来はよく進んでるな
Somehow everything seems to be going brilliantly!
It's time...
いよいよだな
Someone out of this lot is... Kira.
この中の誰かは…
キラ
In that case, let's begin the meeting.
では、定例会議を始めよう
But there's only seven of them, instead of eight...
しかし…八人ではなく、七人だな……
To be continued
竜崎！
この僕が、今存在するキラを捕まえたそのあとで…
キラに…殺人犯になると思うか？
そんな人間に見えるか！？